伙计  我得请你离开这里
Buddy, I'm gonna have to ask you to move along.
嘿  你
Hey there!
喂喂
Excuse me?
这里是禁区
This is a restricted area.
女士
Ma'am?
你没事吧
Are you all right?
我们该找个安逸的地方
We should go somewhere relaxing, you know,
可以什么都不做  就那么待着
where we can just hang, don't you think?
做蜜月计划之前
Before we plan the honeymoon,
-是不是该先选日子  -不
- shouldn't we set a wedding date first? - No.
因为警局还没
'cause the department hasn't even said
准你的假
if you can have time off yet.
而且  计划蜜月能帮我们定日子
Besides, planning a honeymoon will help us set a date.
好吧  你说说
Okay. I can't wait to hear about this.
你总不想雨季去泰国
What, you don't want to go to Thailand during monsoon season, do you?
或者冬天去新西兰
Or New Zealand in the winter?
你先想好要去哪
No. You decide where you wanna go,
然后想好什么时候去最好
the best time to be there.
这样婚礼日子就定下来了
Boom. Lobby for those dates.
新西兰
New Zealand?
卡塞尔  你是想借我们的蜜月
Castle, are you using our honeymoon
去中土游玩吗
as an excuse to go and tour middle-earth?
你同意我就去
I'm game if you are.
我想要更浪漫而不那么霍比特的蜜月
I was hoping for something more romantic and less hobbit-y.
为什么大家都认为浪漫跟霍比特毫不相干
Why does everyone always think those two are mutually exclusive?
而且应该是一个我们两个都没去过的地方
And it should be a place that neither of us have ever been to.
同意  我们找个完美的地方
Agreed. A perfect spot that will be ours
-独享甜蜜时光  -比如巴塞罗那
- and ours alone. - Like Barcelona.
我带梅瑞狄斯去了那儿
That's where I took Meredith.
好吧
Okay. Um...
格拉格斯  我一直想去那儿
Galagos, I've always wanted to go there.
-金娜  -你逗我呢
- Gina. - Seriously?
嗯  我们的蜜月是旋风狂扫式的
Yeah, part of our whirlwind honeymoon tour.
好吧  瑞士阿尔卑斯山  听说那里很美
Fine. Swiss Alps. I hear they're breathtaking.
-是啊  -不会吧
- They are. - No.
嗯  我跟梅瑞狄斯以前冬天会去那儿
Yeah. That's where, uh, Meredith and I used to winter.
这样吧  我觉得更明智的做法
You know what? I think a better plan
是你列出来这世界上
would be for you to make a list of all the places in the world
你没去度过蜜月  假期
that you've never honeymooned, vacationed,
或者迎娶你前妻的地方
or married any of your other wives.
能多难啊
How hard could it be?
阿尔巴尼亚和芬兰  就这两个地方了吗
Albania and Finland-- that's all you've got left.
我们常出去旅行嘛
Well, we traveled a lot.
我肯定还能想到其他的地方
Well, I'm sure I can think of some other places.
我想去暖和点的地方
Yeah, well, my vote's for someplace warmer.
有道理
Ah, maybe you're right.
或许我们该先选日子
Maybe we should just... focus on setting a date.
莱恩
Hey, Ryan.
蕾妮怎么了
What's going on with Lanie?
这件案子让她有点受触动
Uh, this case just hit a little close to home.
怎么了
Why? What happened?
夜班保安
A security guard on the night shift
发现被害人吊死在那根梁上
found the victim hanging from that beam.
确认死者是帕姆·霍奇斯  32岁
We I.D.'d her as Pam Hodges, 32.
勒着脖子吊死的吗
Hanging, as in, by the neck?
对  但真正诡异的是她的长相
Yeah. But what's really bizarre is the way the victim looks.
这是蕾妮的姐姐吗
Is that Lanie's sister?
蕾妮没有姐妹
Lanie doesn't have a sister.
-帕姆·霍奇斯和蕾妮有血缘关系吗  -没有
- Are Pam Hodges and Lanie related? - Nope.
但人说这世上总有个跟我们长得一样的人
But they say we all have a twin out there somewhere.
看来这就是我的那个了
I guess this one's mine.
蕾妮  初步尸检结果可以待会儿说
Lanie, we can deal with the preliminaries later.
我一开始是吓了一跳
I was shook up at first,
但现在没事了  她死于凌晨两点到四点间
but I'm fine now. She died between 2:00 and 4:00 a.m.
她的脖子没断  因为凶手对套索动了手脚
Her neck did not break because the killer rigged the wires
让她的脚刚刚离地
so her feet were just off the ground.
她大概是勒死的
She probably was strangled to death.
那么细的绳索怎么没断
How does a wire that thin not snap?
是高强度钓丝
It's high-test fishing line,
大多体育用品店都有售
available at most sporting goods stores.
那么  别人看起来
So then... it would have seemed
会以为她只是站在码头上
like she was just standing there on the dock.
我们来的时候她就是那个样
That's how she looked when we rolled up.
很诡异
It was freaky.
或许这就是凶手的目的
It's what her killer was going for.
让她的尸体组成一幅画面
He put her body on display to create a tableau.
他很有信心  厚颜无耻
He's confident... brazen.
或许这不是第一次了
Yeah, like he'd done it before?
联系联调局
Contact the FBI.
看看他们数据库里有没有类似的案件
See if they have any similar murders in their databases.
-有目击者吗  -目前没有
- Do we have any witnesses? - No, not so far.
保安发现被害人之前
Security guard had rousted a homeless guy
赶走了一个流浪汉
before he found the victim.
警员还在找他
Uniforms are still trying to track him down,
好问问他看到什么没
see if he saw anything.
关于帕姆·霍奇斯都查到了什么
What do we know about Pam Hodges?
她来自佛罗里达州  在坦帕市过着边缘生活
She's from Tampa, Florida, where she lived on the fringes,
大概有六次因卖淫被捕
racked up about a half a dozen busts for solicitation.
这是一年以前的她
This is her about a year ago.
看来她境遇有所好转
I'd say she came up in the world.
她现在可比当时
She looks a heck of a lot better now
气色好多了
than she did back then...
就是没气了
Aside from the being-dead part.
-她为什么来纽约  -不知道
- Why was she in New York? - Don't know yet.
她七个月前搬来了这里
She moved here seven months ago.
-纽约的驾照  地址在布鲁克林  -好
- New York driver's license with a Brooklyn address. - All right.
查查那个地址  看看她是否有亲人在这儿
Check her address, see if she's got any family here.
对  帕姆是我侄女
Yes, Pam's my niece.
她在我家待了几周
She stayed at my place for a few weeks
然后搬进了城里
when she moved to the city.
你知道她为什么搬来这里吗  霍奇斯先生
Do you know why she came to town, Mr. Hodges?
她说她需要重新开始
Well, she said she needed a fresh start
-而且她得到了份工作  -什么工作
- and she had a job offer. - Doing what?
我担心帕姆又会去站街
I was afraid Pam would start working the streets again.
她告诉家人再也不会重操旧业时
She burned a lot of bridges by telling the family
也断了很多后路
she would go straight and never doing it.
但这次不同
But this time was different.
帕姆说要搬就搬出了我家
Pam moved out of my house when she said she would.
她有了一份新工作
She started working a job.
几个月前  我和她一起吃了午饭
A few months back, I met her for lunch.
我几乎都认不出她了
And I almost didn't recognize her,
她看上去很好  很幸福
she looked so good. Pam was happy.
她说这份新工作就是她梦寐以求的
She said this new job was just what she needed.
你对她的工作有了解吗
What do you know about this job?
-她在哪上班  -她不肯说太多
- Where did she work? - She wouldn't talk about it much,
只说是份正经工作
except to say that it was legit
她得到了很好的照顾
and that she was being taken care of.
她搬走后  你知道她住哪里吗
Do you know where she moved to after she left your place?
那天  我和她打了一辆车
Well, she and I shared a cab that day,
她在西区高速旁的一幢楼前下了车
and it dropped her off at a building off the west side highway.
但我可以说  帕姆真的有了很大改观
I'll tell you this-- Pam took a big step up.
很大改观
A big step up?
简直是质的飞跃
This is a giant leap.
这可是最高档的豪宅
This is a--this is a vault into the stratosphere.
一个来自坦帕的前妓女
How does a former streetwalker from Tampa
怎么负担得起这样的房子
afford a place like this?
有人来找过她吗
She ever get any visitors?
-有可能她就在家里接客  -不是的  先生
- Possible that she, uh, worked out of the home? - No, sir.
这不可能
That is not possible.
那这租金是谁付的
Well, then who paid for rent?
探长  我们在保护客户隐私方面
Detective, we have a well-earned reputation for discretion...
一直有着很好的口碑
and guarding the privacy of our clients.
有谋杀就没有隐私可言了
Privacy ends when murder begins.
马上告诉我是谁在支付这套房的房租
Now I want the name of whoever is paying for this unit.
如果你不知道  马上去给我查
And if you don't have that, then go get it.
我爱死你生气的样子了
I love when you get angry.
我是说生别人的气  不是对我
I mean, at other people, besides me.
卡塞尔  你看这些大衣
Castle, look at these coats.
这里起码挂着两万块呢
There's at least 20 grand hanging here.
不论是谁给她的租的房子也给她买了衣服
So whoever was paying her rent bought her wardrobe, too.
这衣服  这豪宅  她的妓女背景
These coats, this insane place, her history as a hooker,
还有得到了很好照顾的工作
and now this job where she's well taken care of?
所有的一切都指向一点
All points to one thing.
她是某人的情妇
She was someone's mistress.
而她的干爹还没露面
And her sugar daddy hasn't come forward
或是没举报她的失踪
or reported her missing.
他最起码
At the very least,
了解她的生活
he knows about her life.
最坏的情况  他就是凶手
At the very most, he's the one who took it.
假如帕姆是被包养的
If Pam was a kept woman,
那他一定在这里出现过
then he's been to this apartment.
我得叫鉴证组的人来这里收集指纹
I'm gonna get ahold of C.S.U., have them sweep for prints
这样我们就能知道谁在这里待过
so we can find out who's been here.
同时  我们也可以看看这里有什么东西
While we're at it, we should take a look and see what's on this.
这里可能有他们的合影
She might have taken a picture of him.
看起来她没拍合影
It doesn't look like she did.
这里大多数都是标准的纽约风景照
These are mostly standard tourist snapshots of New York.
没有人物照  朋友  男朋友吗
No pictures of people, friends, boyfriends?
目前没有发现
I haven't found any so far.
继续找  好吗
Keep looking, okay?
同时关注背景中的人像
And check the faces in the background,
看看是否有人重复出现
see if any of them show up again.
这些照片很可能就是我们的希望
Those photos might be our best bet.
谢谢
Thanks.
看来租房人信息没查到喽
I take it this means we hit a wall on who rents the apartment?
房子是一家叫格莱格斯·贝克的公司租的
The lease is held and paid for by Gregs-Baker,
是一家注册在伯利兹的壳公司
which is a shell corporation based out of Belize,
公司的设立方式确保其无法查证
and it was set up in such a way as to make it untraceable.
好吧  那通话记录和信用卡呢
All right, well, what about phone records and credit cards?
这一定能告诉我们帕姆·霍奇斯和谁在一起
It must point to who Pam Hodges was spending time with.
她很少用电话
She barely used her phone.
她的信用卡账单倒是不少
And even though she racked up huge credit card bills,
不过大多是用在买衣服  鞋子和做头发
it was mostly for shoes and clothes and hair salons.
也是由格莱格斯·贝克公司按月支付的
And it was paid for monthly by Gregs-Baker.
鉴证组在她的公寓有发现吗
Well, what did C.S.U. Find at her apartment?
只有她的指纹  没别人的
Her prints. No one else's.
-这到底是怎么了  -我也不知道
- What the hell is going on here? - I don't know.
但是有人在掩盖行踪方面
But someone is doing an incredible job
做得非常到位
of covering their tracks.
喂  蕾妮
Hey, Lanie.
凯特
Kate...
你下来一下吧
I need you to get down here.
好  我们马上来
Okay, we're on our way.
不要卡塞尔  就你来
Not Castle. Just you.
怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
帕姆·霍奇斯近期做过整容  脸颊内有植入物
Pam Hodges recently had a cheek plastic put in.
使得她的脸变宽  就像我一样
It made her face broader, like mine.
-好吧  -她用的洗发水
- Okay. - Her hair products,
口红  指甲油
her lipstick, her nail polish--
都跟我用的一模一样
they're all the same as the ones I use.
蕾妮  你只不过是碰巧和被害人用的
Lanie, you're just picking up on things that are similar
-一样而已  -我也一直这样安慰自己
- with the victim. - That's what I kept telling myself.
然后我发现了这个
Then I found this.
好吧  这我之前见过
Okay, all right. I've seen this before.
这是"内在力量"的意思
It--it means "Inner strength."
我知道这是什么意思  凯特
I know what it means, Kate.
你看
Look.
我在同样的位置有着一模一样的纹身
I have the same exact tattoo in the same place.
这怎么可能
How's that even possible?
我们这么像并非巧合
It's no accident we could be twins.
是有人故意要把她弄成和我一样
Somebody went out of their way to make her look like me.
等等  你是说
Wait a minute. So you're saying
帕姆·霍奇斯想弄成和蕾妮一样
that Pam Hodges was trying to look like Lanie?
从纹身和整容手术来看
Given the tattoo and the surgery,
没有其他解释了
I just don't see another explanation.
但她为什么要这样呢
Yeah, but why would she do that?
因为她干爹喜欢她这样
Because her sugar daddy wanted her to.
有可能他在坦帕找到她
Maybe he found her down in tampa,
把她运过来  按自己的喜好打扮她
shipped her up here, set her up in style.
对于一个妓女来说
I mean, to a streetwalker,
这是最轻松的活了
that would seem like the greatest gig ever,
她只要任他把自己塑造成蕾妮的样子就行
and all she'd have to do is let him remake her into Lanie.
-谢了  LT  -不过更加扭曲
- Thanks, L.T. - Yeah, but even more twisted.
这家伙肯定认识蕾妮
So this guy has to know Lanie.
但她似乎不认识他
Only she doesn't seem to know him.
不过她还是会录口供的
But she's still coming in to give us a statement.
帕姆大厦的人怎么说
Now, what about the staff in Pam's building?
有没有提供其他的详细资料
Did they give us any more details?
没  没人见过有人去找她
No, none of them remember seeing any guys coming to see her.
也许有其他的方法可以找到这个人
You know, there might be another way for us to trace this guy.
脸颊植入物上有序列号
The cheek implants have serial numbers.
也许可以帮我们找到帕姆的整形医生
Maybe that'll lead us to Pam's surgeon.
也许干爹藏起来还有别的原因
There might be another reason her sugar daddy's laying low.
联调局的数据库显示
FBI database shows
还有两人被用金属钓丝勒死
two other victims strangled with metal fishing line
尸体摆成吊死状
and their bodies staged--
一个在迈阿密  另一个在劳德代尔堡
one in Miami, one in Fort Lauderdale,
案子都没破  没有嫌疑人
both unsolved, no suspects.
死者来自佛罗里达  也许他在那儿结识了她
Well, our victim's from Florida. Maybe he knew her from there.
调出那两起案子的文件  和我们这个作对比
Order the homicide files, check 'em against our case.
同时  排查帕姆去过的商店和沙龙
In the meantime, canvass the stores and the salons Pam went to.
也许她和别人透露过
Maybe she confided in someone,
或者有人见过她和他一起
or someone might have seen her with this guy.
一位法医竟然在调查她二重身的凶手
An M.E. investigates the murder of her own doppelganger.
如果不是发生在蕾妮身上  一定是个好故事
It'd be a great story, if Lanie weren't living it.
我们一定漏掉了什么  卡塞尔
There's something that we're missing here, Castle.
佛罗里达发生两起相似案件
Two similar murders in Florida.
死者也来自佛罗里达
Our victim, also from Florida.
还有她跟蕾妮外貌上的相似
But then there's this whole Lanie and her look-a-like angle.
这是怎么回事
How does that fit in?
完全想不出来
I have no idea.
脸颊植入物有线索
We got a hit on those cheek implants.
查到了曼哈顿一位整容医生
They were traced to a Manhattan cosmetic surgeon--
凯莉·尼曼医生
a Dr. Kelly Nieman.
我很想知道凯莉·尼曼医生要怎么说
Well, I for one, am very interested in what Dr. Nieman has to say.
还有
In the meantime,
蕾妮想让埃斯波西托给她录口供
Lanie wants to give her statement to Esposito.
你不是罪犯  蕾妮
You're not a perp, Lanie.
我们不该在这里  以这种方式谈话
It doesn't seem right-- us talking in here like this.
我想要个私密的地方
I wanted to be somewhere private.
-赶紧开始吧  好吗  -好
- So let's get on with this, okay? - Okay.
你能不能想到任何
Um... so can you think of anyone
会做这种事的人
who would do a thing like this?
想不到
No.
过去半年内你都和谁在一起过
Who have you been with in the last six months,
除了我  我知道我们没有定下来
besides me? I mean, I know we're not exclusive.
没有
No one.
我要知道真相  无论真相是什么
I need the truth-- whatever it is.
我说的就是真相
I'm telling you the truth.
那他们怎么知道纹身的事
Then how do they know about the tattoo?
你才纹了三个月  对吧
You've only had it three months, right?
如果你没脱衣服别人是看不见的
No one could see it unless you're naked.
那你有没有不小心和别人讲过
Well, did you happen to mention it to anyone?
当然没有了
Of course not.
我只给你一个人看过
You are the only person I ever showed it to.
等一下  还是有地方不对
Wait. Still, something's not right.
没道理啊
This--this doesn't make sense.
快点  蕾妮  好好想想
Come on, Lanie. Think.
有人接近过你
Someone got close to you.
看过那个纹身
Someone saw that tattoo.
是谁
Who was it?
-我的天  -怎么了
- Oh, my God. - What?
两个月前有个晚上很奇怪
I had a weird... night two months back.
怎么个奇怪法
Weird how?
部门有人升职
Someone at work got promoted,
所以我们一堆人去夜店庆祝
and a bunch of us hit a nightclub to celebrate.
大家跳得很欢  所以我待到很晚
And some hot jazz was going, so I stayed late.
第二天早上醒来的时候
When I woke up the next day,
我完全不记得我是怎么回家的
I couldn't remember how I got home.
等等  你什么时候打破你只喝两杯的规矩了
Wa-wait, since when do you go busting your 2-drink limit?
我没有  那天晚上也没有
I don't, and I didn't that night either.
会不会就是那天晚上呢
What... What if this is when it happened?
他往我酒里下药
What if he put something in my drink
把我带回家
and took me to my place
然后所有这一切都因我而起
and all of this started because of me?
你找我  发现了什么
I got your message. What'd you find?
帕姆的照片里没有发现
Nothing in Pam's pictures,
但是我扫描了相机里的记忆卡
but I scanned the camera's memory card,
恢复了一张删除的照片
and I recovered a deleted picture file.
这是死者  什么时候拍的
That's our victim. When was this taken?
根据图片详情  是昨天下午
Based on the J.P.E.G. data, yesterday afternoon.
就是她被害之前几小时
So just a few hours before she was killed.
找到那个船坞  并查出船主是谁
Let's locate that marina and find out who owns that boat.
纽约警局  我需要
N.Y.P.D. I need--
抱歉  你们有预约吗
I'm sorry... do you have an appointment?
我们找尼曼医生
We're here to see Dr. Nieman.
-我可以问一下这是怎么回事吗  -不行
- Can I ask what this is regarding? - No.
抱歉  尼曼医生
I'm sorry, Dr. Nieman.
抱歉打扰了  这是
I apologize for the intrusion. This is--
贝克特探长  卡塞尔先生
Detective Beckett. Mr. Castle.
请进  请坐
Uh, please come in. Have a seat.
作为一个孜孜不倦的自我推销者
As a tireless self-promoter,
我送你一支笔吧
let me offer you one of my pens.
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
我们只是想问你几个问题
We're just here to ask you a few questions.
我想说  你的脸真是太美了  探长
Oh, can I just say, you have an amazing face, detective?
那...
And what about, uh...
那我的呢
What about my face?
很有潜质
Uh... amazing potential.
不如讨论一下帕姆·霍奇斯的脸吧
Why don't we talk about Pam Hodges' face
和她被害的事
and the fact that she was murdered?
天啊  怎么回事
Jeez. What happened?
她是你的顾客  对吧
She was one of your patients. Is that correct?
是的  我给她做了一下修整
Uh, yes. Yes, I performed some refinements.
在谁的授意下呢
And at whose behest?
她自己
Hers.
她给我带来了一张她朋友的照片
She actually brought me a picture of a friend of hers.
她们脸型相似
They had similar facial structure,
帕姆想接近她朋友的长相
and Pam wanted to look a bit more like her friend.
等等  我问你  顾客来这里
Wait. Let me get this straight. So people come in
要求整容成别人的模样
and ask to look like other people,
你们就照做
and you just do it?
病人带照片过来也不足为奇
Well, it's not unusual for patients to bring me photos--
通常是模特或演员的照片  用作参考
Usually of models or actors-- for reference.
她给你看的这些照片
And these photos she showed you,
是在哪拍的
where were they taken?
像是酒吧或俱乐部的快照
They looked like snapshots from a bar or a club,
我记得是这样
as I recall.
她和别人一起来过吗
Did she ever come here with anyone, um...
她提到过她生活中的人吗
Did she ever mention any of the men in her life?
恐怕没有
No, I'm afraid not.
是谁付了她整容的费用
And who was it that paid for these new cheeks of hers?
是她付的  公司支票
She did... with a company check.
格莱格斯·贝克吗
From Gregs-Baker?
我得再查一下  不过听起来没错
I'd have to look, but that-- that sounds right.
失陪一下
Um, excuse me.
那个  你认真的吗
Okay. Seriously?
"很有潜质"
"Amazing potential"?
我很乐意帮你挖掘潜力
And I'd love to help you realize it.
-说吧  -我们查到了照片上的船坞
- Yeah, hey. - We tracked down that marina from the photo.
是长岛的迎风湾
It's Windward Cove in Long Island.
-我们正在这儿  -帕姆登的是谁的船
- We're here right now. - Who's boat was Pam on?
船登记在佛罗里达的鲁迪·霍林斯名下
It's registered out of Florida to a Rudy Hollings.
好  他是什么情况
Okay, so what do we know about him?
一无所知  只知道帕姆遇害当晚
Not a damn thing, except for Pam was on his boat
在他的船上
the night she was murdered.
-我们要登船了  安全了再给你打电话  -好
- We're about to board. I'll call you when it's secure. - Okay.
纽约警局  纽约警局
N.Y.P.D.! N.Y.P.D.!
警察  前方有个疑犯
Police! Got a suspect up ahead!
四点钟方向  亮出双手
4:00! Let me see your hands!
马上亮出双手
Let me see your hands right now!
-亮出双手  -亮出双手  快
- Let me see your hands! - Show me your hands, right now!
-亮出双手  -快亮出双手
- Let me see your hands! - Show us your hands now!
怎么了
What?
-埃斯波西托  出去  别看  -什么意思
- Espo, go outside. Don't look, man. - What do you mean?
你说什么  叫我出去
What are you talking about, go outside? Huh?
让我看
Let me see.
是我
It's me.
死者是丹尼尔·桑托斯
Our victim is Daniel Santos
和帕姆·霍奇斯一样  他被钓丝吊着
like Pam Hodges, he was hung with fishing line.
不过桑托斯没有做过整容手术的迹象
Although Santos shows no sign of cosmetic surgery,
凶手  由于不明原因
this killer-- for reasons unknown--
显然精心挑选了两名
has clearly selected two victims
样貌和我们两名警员相似的人下手
who bear a deliberate resemblance to members of our own police family.
犯罪现场有什么线索
Now, what did the crime scene give us?
没有指纹和痕量证据
Well, there's no prints or trace evidence.
我们只知道吊着桑托斯的装备
All we know is that the rig Santos was hung from
是用标准五金店管子搭建
was built from standard hardware store pipe,
装钓丝的卷线器
and that the fishing reel that fed the line
是2005年在北卡罗来纳州一家鱼饵店买的
was bought from a bait shop in North Carolina in 2005.
船主的资料呢
Where are we on the owner of the boat?
鲁迪·霍林斯  他在西班牙待了一年
Rudy Hollings--he's been in Spain for a year.
他说不知道谁会利用他的船杀人
He said he had no idea who would've used his boat to commit a murder.
那就是有人知道他的出行计划
So somebody could have been aware of his travel plans?
也有可能是凶手对船只有所了解
It's also possible if the killer knew boats,
他通过观察找到了没有人在使用的船
uh, they were looking for telltale signs the boat wasn't in use.
对  这可能就是他选这只船的原因  长官
Yeah, that's probably why he picked it, sir.
他知道自己能不受干扰地杀死丹尼尔·桑托斯
He knew he could kill Daniel Santos undisturbed.
桑托斯先生的背景呢
Well, what do we know about Mr. Santos?
他一年前从乔治亚州搬来这里
He moved here from Georgia about a year ago,
我还在找他目前的住址
uh, I'm still trying to find a current address.
我和他的父母谈过
I did speak with his parents.
他们告诉我他之前做脱衣舞男
They told me that he worked as a male stripper.
三个月前  他打电话给父母
Three months ago, he called his parents
说他不跳脱衣舞了
to tell them that he quit stripping,
找到了一份很好的演出机会
and he had landed a big-time gig.
他们知道是什么演出吗
Did they know what this gig was?
不知道  他和帕姆·霍奇斯一样闪烁其词
No. He was vague, just like Pam Hodges.
好  我要你  埃斯波西托警探
Okay. So I need you, Detective Esposito,
和帕里什医生回顾一遍你们共同处理的所有案件
and Dr. Parish to go over all the cases that you worked together.
-看有没有哪个有关人员有嫌疑  -是  长官
- See if anyone connected to them presents as a suspect. - Yes, sir.
为了这些死者  和我们自己人
For the sake of these victims-- and our own people--
查出凶手
Find this killer.
我还是不懂
I still don't get it.
为什么有人会杀害克隆版埃斯波西托和蕾妮
Why would someone kill clones of Esposito and Lanie?
这算是种警告吗
I mean, is it some kind of warning?
或许我们细查丹尼尔·桑托斯的生活
Maybe if we dig deeper into Daniel Santos' life,
问题就迎刃而解了
we'll figure it out.
我想我知道要怎么查他的动向了
I think I've got a lead as to what he was up to.
根据他的预付费借记卡记录
According to his pre-paid debit card records,
他每周一  周三  周五下午
he bought a latte at the same midtown building
都在同一幢市中心大楼里买一杯拿铁
every Monday, Wednesday, and Friday afternoon.
-好像他有固定约会  -是的
- As if he was keeping some kind of regular appointment? - He did.
根据门卫的口供
According to the doorman,
他在见一个叫伊恩·福勒的医生
he was meeting with a Dr. Ian Fuller.
他是个治疗师
He's some kind of a therapist.
事实上  我是个语言治疗师
Actually, I'm a speech therapist.
我专门研究减少口音
I specialize in accent reduction.
丹尼尔来自乔治亚州
Uh, so Daniel was from Georgia.
他是不是想改掉
Was he trying to get rid
-他的南方口音  -不止如此
- of his southern accent? - Oh, more than that.
他想改变整个说话方式
He wanted to change his entire speech pattern.
变成什么样
To what end?
他没说  可他非常有决心
He didn't say, but he was very determined
非常明确他的目标
and very specific about his goals.
他还带来了一断想达成的目标的音频文件
He even brought in an audio file of how he wanted to sound.
-你有那份文件吗  -有  我带来了
- Do you have the file? - Yeah, I have it right here.
我这就把它调出来
Let me just, uh, pull it up.
没错
It's true.
比如  我以前是军人
For example, I'm former military,
所以我是个神枪手
Which makes me an expert marksman.
我通常是第一个破门而入的
I'm usually first through the door.
这是埃斯波西托
That's Esposito.
我则是身强体壮的那位
I'm definitely the physical one.
是从那部在分局拍摄的
That's from the documentary
-纪录片里截取的  -我身体一直很棒
- we shot right here at the precinct. - I stay in sick shape.
瞧瞧
Boom!
桑托斯不仅长得像他
Santos wasn't just a look-alike--
-说话也像  -说真的
- He was a sound-alike. - Seriously though...
他的脸  他的发型
His face, the way he cut his hair,
现在他连说话都跟我一样了吗
and now he's trying to talk like me, too?
什么样的神经病会这么做
What kind of sicko is doing this?
我浏览了我们经手的每一件案子
I went through every case we worked on,
一无所获
and nothing jumped out.
我也一样
Yeah, not for me either.
这肯定
It's gotta be--
这肯定是私人恩怨
It's gotta be something personal.
这肯定是知道我们关系的人做的
It's gotta be someone who knows about our relationship.
不管他是谁  肯定是个变态
Well, whoever he is, he's a freak.
他让丹尼尔·桑托斯饱受折磨
He made Daniel Santos suffer.
看看皮肤下的出血情况
Look at the bleeding underneath the skin.
他死前那条钓丝嵌入他脖子长达几个小时
That wire bit into his neck for hours before he died.
凶手利用卷线器  让他慢慢死去
The killer used that fishing reel to kill him slowly.
他下一个要找上谁呢
So who is he gonna go after now--
你和我  另一个版本的莱恩和贝克特吗
You and me, some version of Ryan and Beckett?
如果这只是个开始呢
What if this is just the beginning?
会没事的
It'll be okay.
我保证
I promise.
我不会让任何人伤害你
I won't let anything happen to you.
是吗
Yeah?
那你自己呢
What if something happens to you?
兄弟  我们正说到动情处呢
Dude... we're having a moment here.
抱歉
Sorry...
我找到桑托斯工作的脱衣舞俱乐部了
I found the strip club where Santos worked.
他们有他在皇后区的家庭住址
They had a home address for him in Queens.
你还好吧
So how are you doing, man?
我没事  你呢
I'm fine. How are you?
你现在肯定很不好过
It's big-- what you're dealing with.
我只是想说  还有我呢
I just want to put it out there that I'm here for you.
谢了 兄弟
Good to know, man.
我是想说  找人聊聊会有帮助的
The point is, sometimes talking about it helps.
怎么  你想让我分享内心感受吗
So what, you want me to share my feelings now?
很多人都会这么做
Uh, it's what a lot of people would do.
好吧
All right, fine.
我要找到这个人渣
I want to find this piece of garbage,
把他吊起来  看看他爽不爽
string him up, and see how he likes it.
就这样
There...
-我分享了  高兴了吗  -看
- I shared a feeling. Happy now? - See...
感觉好点了吧
Don't you feel better?
-莱恩  -算了
- Ryan... - All right.
楼管说丹尼尔·桑托斯
The super said that Daniel Santos
-最近没怎么来过这  -天啊
- hasn't been around here much lately. - Oh, my god.
-丹尼尔  -不  实际上
- Daniel? - No. No, actually, uh,
哈维尔·埃斯波西托警探  纽约警察
Detective Javier Esposito, N.Y.P.D.
像见鬼了一样
It's like seeing a ghost.
你跟他太像了
You look so much like him.
你认识丹尼尔吗
Yeah, um, so you knew Daniel?
我希望能更了解他
Not as much as I wanted to,
但多少知道些
but a little.
至少知道他完全可以找更好的谋生手段
Enough to know that he was better than what he did for a living.
听说他为了一个很好的机会辞掉了那份工作
We--we heard he quit that job for some big-time gig.
你知道是什么吗
You have any idea what it was?
他说他不能跟别人说这个
He said he couldn't talk about it.
有人来见过他吗
Uh, did people come visit him here?
没人来找丹尼尔
People didn't visit Daniel.
一般都是倒过来
It was more like the other way around.
怎么讲
Meaning what?
我看到过他
I'd see him, uh...
离开这儿  有辆豪华轿车等在前门
leave here and a limo would be waiting out front.
-最近如此吗  -没错
- Was this recently? - Yeah.
他两晚前被接走的
One picked him up two nights ago.
他被杀的那个晚上
The same night he was killed.
你记得那车什么样吗
Do you remember what that vehicle looked like?
黑色
It was black.
城里随处可见的那种
I mean, it was just a regular town car.
但牌照周围有蓝色
But there was... blue around the license plate.
等等  你是说蓝色霓虹灯吗
Wait a minute. Do you mean blue neon?
对  就是那个
Yeah, that was it.
蓝色霓虹灯牌照框
Blue neon license plate frames--
那是蓝月豪轿公司的标志
That's the trademark of Blue Moon Limos.
蓝月公司的经理
That was the manager at the Blue Moon.
他说那辆车把丹尼尔·桑托斯送到了
He said the limo dropped Daniel Santos off
订车人的公寓
at the apartment of the person who ordered it.
不管是谁  可能就是凶手
Well, whoever it is, is probably our killer.
有姓名吗
Did he give you a name?
凯莉·尼曼医生
Yeah, Dr. Kelly Nieman.
她还真是"很有潜力"啊
Well, I would say she has "Amazing potential"...
做杀人犯
as a murderer.
-怎样  -门卫确认
- Well? - The doorman at her building confirms
桑托斯两晚前去过
that Santos visited two nights ago.
而且不是第一次了
And not for the first time.
他说桑托斯经常在医生家过夜
He said Santos was a frequent overnight guest of the good doctor.
两名被害人都与她联系起来了
Which directly connects her to both of our victims.
凯莉·尼曼能制服得了
So are we to believe that Kelly Nieman
正当壮年的桑托斯吗
Overpowered Santos-- a young man in his prime?
她完全做得到
Well, she was more than capable.
根据她的简历  她是跆拳道和
According to her bio, she's a black belt
柔道的双重黑带
in both tae kwon do and jiujitsu.
她还有行船经验且在弗罗里达长大
She also has boating experience and grew up in Florida.
实际上  另两起案件发生时
In fact, she was in Miami at a conference
她就在迈阿密
at the time of the other two murders.
我们有任何能证明她有嫌疑的确凿证据吗
Do we have any hard evidence linking her to these murders?
从一开始就看得出本案凶手十分小心谨慎
It's been clear from the beginning that our killer is very careful.
也就是说没证据
So the answer is no.
这整个案子都建立在推测之上
This entire case is circumstantial,
所以你得撬开她的嘴
which means you're gonna need to break her.
而且机会只此一次
And you got one shot.
尼曼医生
Dr. Nieman...
感谢你能过来
Thank you for coming in.
我有的选吗
Was I offered a choice?
关于你与丹尼尔·桑托斯的关系
I wanted to ask you a few questions
我想问你几个问题
about your relationship with Daniel Santos.
现在我和他可没关系了
Well, I no longer have one.
看来你已经知道他被害了
So you are aware that he's dead.
我在新闻上看的
I watch the news.
但你看上去并不很难过
You don't seem terribly upset by it.
我当然能装得很难过
Well, I suppose I could fake it or lie,
但这对你我来说都很无聊
but that's just as tedious for you as it is for me.
我们之间纯粹是肉体上的关系
It was purely physical with us.
你真的是一个非常美丽的女人
You really are a beautiful woman...
但并不完美
but not perfect.
我能让你完美
I could fix you.
他去你的公寓之后你去了那里
Where did you go after he came to your apartment?
就待在我的公寓里
Hmm. We stayed in.
你没有去过哪个船坞附近
You didn't go by a marina?
我又没有船
I don't have a boat.
但他的遗体就是在一艘船上被发现了
And yet his body was found on one.
在那之前
And prior to that,
他去过你的公寓
he was at your apartment.
-没错  但他又走了  -什么时候
- Yes, but then he left my place. - When?
十点左右
Around 10:00.
丹尼尔·桑托斯和你共度了他最后一天
Daniel Santos spent his last day with you.
帕姆·霍奇斯是你的客户
Pam Hodges was a patient of yours.
他俩都被谋杀了
They were both murdered.
他们唯一的共同点就是你
The only person that they have in common is you.
你也不指望我会相信
Now you don't expect me to believe
这纯粹是个巧合吧
that that's a coincidence, do you?
当然不是巧合
It's not a coincidence at all.
帕姆就是丹尼尔介绍来的
Daniel referred Pam to me as a patient.
这么说他俩认识
So they knew each other?
我们找不到任何证据证明这一点
We don't have any evidence of that.
我确定如果你继续查下去肯定会有所收获
Well, I'm sure you'll find some if you keep looking.
帕姆来见我时  说过是他推荐她来的
When Pam came in, she said that he'd recommended her to me.
我也问你个问题
Let me ask you something.
你想没想到过我被陷害了
Has it occurred to you that I'm being set up here?
谁陷害的你
Set up by whom?
也许这个凶手
Maybe whoever did this
知道我与丹尼尔和帕姆的关系
knew of my connection to Daniel and Pam.
也许这就是他计划的一部分
Maybe this was part of their plan--
浪费你我的时间
to waste your time and mine.
我看不会
I doubt that.
你没法证明我去过什么码头
You'll never prove that I was at those docks
或者船坞  因为我本来就没有
or some marina, because I wasn't.
再说  我又有什么动机杀人呢
Besides... what possible motive would I have for killing anyone?
我跟律师约会过
I've dated lawyers.
我知道你要是不起诉我
I know that if you don't charge me,
我有权离开
I can leave.
别生气  探长
No hard feelings, detective.
你我都是专业人士  你只是在尽职而已
We're both professionals. You're just doing your job.
你寻求正义  我则追求完美
You seek justice, and I seek perfection.
话说回来
In fact...
你要是打算让自己达到完美
whenever you're ready to take this to the next level...
尽管来找我
you come see me.
我什么都没问出来  卡塞尔
I got nothing, Castle. I--
我甚至没法把她和佛罗里达的凶案联系起来
I can't even tie her to the Florida murders,
只知道案发时她在那一带
other than the fact that she was in the area when they occurred.
有些你不爱听的话
Can I say something that'll...
我不知当说不当说
probably annoy you?
我就是不让你说你不也照样开口
Since when do you ask for permission?
也对
Touche.
如果尼曼医生真的不是凶手呢
What if Dr. Nieman isn't our killer?
卡塞尔  你也看见她在审讯室的表现了
Castle, you saw her in there.
她在跟我打太极呢
She was toying with me.
她肯定脱不了干系
She's involved in this.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
我同意  她不是热情亲切的那种
I admit... she's not warm and cuddly.
但这并不意味着她有罪
But that doesn't make her guilty.
按说你应该是最不可能相信她的了
How can you of all people buy her story?
因为此时此刻  这比我们的推理更合理
Because at this point, it makes more sense than ours does.
你想一想
Just... consider this.
这整个案子  凶手都抢先我们一步
All along, this killer has been one step ahead of us--
人证物证都没有  公司也是个空壳
no evidence, no witnesses, phantom corporations.
这个人引得我们原地打转
He or she has us chasing our tails.
这同一个凶手  怎么会突然间叫了辆豪车
So why, suddenly, does this same person order a limo
使被害人死亡当天  自己跟他在一起
placing her with Santos the night he died?
难道是新手疏忽了
Rookie mistake.
也许这根本不是个疏忽
Or maybe it's not a mistake at all.
也许凯莉·尼曼在下一盘更大的棋
Maybe Kelly Nieman is playing a much deeper game.
也许正是因为她自信
Maybe she's so confident
没有证据能把她和凶案联系起来
that we can't tie her to these murders,
所以有意留下线索引我们查到她头上
that she's letting the trail lead straight back to her.
那个  似乎不太可能
Um... that's looking pretty unlikely.
为什么
Why?
她的不在场证明无懈可击
Her alibi's ironclad.
两起凶案她都没法作案  但是
She's no good for either of the murders. But...
我们似乎找到了可能犯案的人
we might have found somebody who is.
早跟你说过
Told you.
这是凯莉·尼曼公寓外
This is from a traffic cam
一街区处的交通探头拍的画面
a block from Kelly Nieman's apartment.
那是丹尼尔·桑托斯
That's Daniel Santos.
时间显示是10点07分  这么说凯莉没撒谎
The timecode is 10:07. So Kelly was telling the truth.
他确实是在十点前后离开的
He did leave around 10:00.
再接着看
Yeah, now watch this.
能拉近镜头看清驾驶员的相貌吗
Can we get a closer look at the driver?
只拍到这一个角度
No, this is our only angle.
不管那人是谁  桑托斯认识他
Well, whoever he is, Santos knows him.
我们查了车牌
Now we tried running the plate...
结果是从别的车子上偷来的
But it was stolen off another car.
死路一条
So no good there.
但托瑞注意到后车窗上有张贴纸
But Tory noticed a decal in the back window.
是停车证
It's a parking pass.
迈阿密的"珊瑚之路船坞"
For "Coral Way Marina" in Miami.
不管他是谁  他可能跟佛罗里达的凶案有关
So whoever he is, he could be connected to our Florida murders.
我给船坞打了电话
I called the marina.
尽管停车证已经过期
Even though the parking pass is expired,
他们还是查出了这是给什么人的
they were able to tell us who it was issued to--
那人叫卡尔·马修斯
one Carl Matthews.
卡尔·马修斯是谁
And who is Carl Matthews?
把他的驾照照片调出来
Show us the DMV photo, please.
现在认识了吗
Recognize him now?
这是码头的保安
That's the security guard from the dock.
我们现在认为  是卡尔·马修斯
We now believe that Carl Matthews killed
杀害了丹尼尔·桑托斯和帕姆·霍奇斯
both Daniel Santos and Pam Hodges.
那个发现她尸体的蠢蛋保安吗
That security mook that found her?
我们怎么让他逃走的
How did we let him slip away?
马修斯没有犯罪记录  当时没觉得他有嫌疑
Matthews didn't have a record, and nothing on him popped.
在马修斯发现帕姆·霍奇斯的尸体一天后
Now the day after Matthews "found" Pam Hodges dead,
他就辞职了  说他太难过无法工作
he quit his job, saying he was too upset to work.
现在他行踪不明
Now he's in the wind.
我打赌  佛罗里达的案子也是他干的
I'll bet this scumbag did the Florida murders, too.
看来是这样的
It looks that way.
他曾在佛罗里达的渔船出租公司工作
He crewed fishing charters in Florida,
这说明他熟悉船只
which means he knows his way around boats.
2010年  他消失了
Now, in 2010, he went off the grid,
直到一年前  他又出现在纽约
and then he resurfaced about a year ago in New York
在码头工作
when he took at job at the docks.
下一步打算怎么办
What's your next move?
我们已经对马修斯和他的车放出通缉令
We've got an alert out on Matthews and his car,
但最可能找到他的办法是联系他的家人
but... our best bet is to get in contact with his family,
朋友  同事  或者前妻
his friends, co-workers, ex-wives.
他认识的人中  肯定有人知道他的下落
Someone in his life has to know where he is
和他接下来想干什么
and what his next move might be.
有进展吗
Any news?
还没有  但我们会找到他的
No, not yet, but we'll find him.
有什么不对劲吗
What's wrong?
卡尔·马修斯不对劲  他在这个故事里格格不入
Carl Matthews is wrong. He doesn't fit the story.
怎么格格不入了
How doesn't he fit?
在佛罗里达  他就是个整天泡海滩的人
In Florida, he's basically a beach bum.
在纽约他也只是保安
Here he's a security guard.
这样的人怎么策划得出这样的案子
H-how's a guy like that pull this off?
也许他就是...
Maybe he just...
比他给人的印象聪明得多吧
reads more intelligent than he is on paper.
那钱怎么解释
What about the money--
给帕姆·霍奇斯的手术费
enough to put Pam Hodges in for surgery?
他抢银行或者贩毒了吧
He robbed a bank, or he was dealing drugs.
我也不知道
I-I don't know. You know,
他离开佛罗里达后就没有消息了
he fell off the grid after he left Florida.
提到这个  他人在佛罗里达
Speaking of which, he's in Florida.
没有消息  从没被逮捕过
He's off the grid. He's never been arrested.
那他为什么对蕾妮和埃斯波西托那么着迷
Why the fixation with Lanie and Esposito?
我们没有全部答案  卡塞尔
We don't have all of the answers, Castle,
至少目前没有
Not right now, at least.
但所有的证据都指向马修斯
But all of the evidence is pointing to Matthews.
我同意
I agree with you.
我只是觉得他不是单干
I just don't think he's working alone.
我觉得  他还有个同伙
I think he has a partner.
比如尼曼医生吗
Like who, Dr. Nieman?
不对
No.
是我们的老相识了
Someone we've dealt with before.
-3XK  3XK早死了  -是吗
- 3XK? 3XK is dead. - Is he?
如果我们能在3XK的档案里找到卡尔·马修斯呢
And what if we find Carl Matthews' name in his case files?
杰瑞·泰森从桥上冲下去了
Jerry Tyson fell off that bridge.
从30多米高的桥上跌入水中
It was a hundred-foot drop into the water.
有人找到他的尸体了吗
Was his body ever found?
没人从那么高的地方摔下去还能活命
Nobody could survive that fall.
杰瑞·泰森就能
Jerry Tyson could.
卡塞尔  听听你自己说的话
Castle, listen to yourself.
没有任何泰森还活着的证据
There's not a shred of evidence that Tyson is alive,
更别说参与这桩案子了
let alone involved in this.
泰森不会留下证据
Tyson doesn't leave evidence,
除了他希望我们找到
not unless he wants us to find it,
比如已删除的照片
like that deleted photo.
没有证据  加上一丝不苟的算计
No evidence, plus meticulous planning--
就是3XK的特点  这次案子确实符合这些
that's vintage 3XK, and this case has it in spades.
-卡塞尔  -知道3XK还有什么经典手法吗
- Castle... - And you want to know some other 3XK classics--
利用长相相似的人们
using people that look like other people.
找一个杀手代替自己杀人
Using a killer to act on his behalf.
贝克特  你怎么就看不出来呢
Beckett, how can you not see it?
我看到的是你的愧疚
What I see is the guilt that you feel.
这事跟我无关
This isn't about me.
听着  泰森逃跑时  他骗倒了我们所有人
Look, when Tyson escaped, he outsmarted all of us.
但你一直觉得那是你的错
But you've always blamed yourself.
因为就是我的错...
Because I'm to blame...
是他  是杰瑞·泰森
It's him-- it's Jerry Tyson.
别追着死人不放  卡塞尔
Don't chase ghosts, Castle.
好吗  不值得  相信我
Okay? It's not worth it, trust me.
探长
Detective!
3XK的档案好像全都不见了
Looks like the 3XK files are gone.
什么叫不见了
What do you mean, they're gone?
全都没了吗  怎么会这样
All of them? How?
肯定是有人领走了
Somebody must have signed them out.
是谁
Who?
如果能想到别的东西  请务必联系我  谢谢
Well, let me know if you can think of anything else, all right? Thanks.
3XK的档案呢
Where are the 3XK files?
你们说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢
你的签名在表单上
Your name is on the signature sheet.
不  才没有
No, it's not.
有  三天前的签名
Yeah, from three days ago.
你把档案都领走了
You checked those files out.
我没领走任何档案
I didn't check out any files.
一定有人弄错了
Somebody messed up.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
有谁能告诉我们  究竟是怎么回事吗
Someone want to tell us what the hell is going on?
电话是法医办公室主任打来的
That was the head of the M.E.'s office.
所有3XK案件死者的报告
Reports, lab work, D.N.A., tissue samples
实验室化验单  DNA和组织样本
of every suspected 3XK victim were checked out...
全被蕾妮取走了
by Lanie.
只不过不是真的蕾妮
Only not the real Lanie.
你是说那个混蛋回来了
Are you saying the son of a bitch is back?
这解释了死者的外貌相似
That explains the look-alikes....
还有桑托斯模仿我声音的原因
And why Santos tried to sound like me.
杰瑞·泰森消失了还不够
It's not enough that Jerry Tyson disappeared.
他还想让他的案子也消失
He wanted his murders to disappear, too.
不止是证据没了
And it's not just evidence.
他的杀人手法  死者偏好
It's his M.O.s, victim preferences,
上百条能反映其心理特征的案件细节
all the hundreds of tiny case details that can reveal psychology
这本可揭露他下落和接下来的行动
as to where he is, where he might be going next.
全没了  好像他一下子洗白了
It's all gone.... like he's got a clean slate.
或许没都洗掉
Maybe not completely clean.
打给关押泰森的监狱
Call the prison where Tyson did time.
在他的记录也消失前  让他们保管好
Have them secure his records before they disappear, too,
然后把复印件发给我们
And then have them send us the copies.
我这就去办
Oh, I'm all over it.
一辆巡逻车刚发现马修斯的车
A cruiser just spotted Matthews' car
停在皇后区的星爆旅馆
at the Starburst Motel in Queens.
我们当时就把杰瑞·泰森安置在那儿
That's the same motel where we put up Jerry Tyson.
多谢
Thanks.
前台说他在47号房
Front desk says he's in room 47.
泰森当时也在那间房
That's the same room Tyson was in.
那是他的车
There's his car.
47号房的灯亮着
Lights out in room 47.
听着  卡塞尔
Listen, castle.
我们不清楚上面什么情况
We don't know what's waiting for us up there.
你得待在这儿  好吗
You need to stay here, okay?
你小心点
You be careful.
走吧
Let's go.
警察  纽约警局
Police! N.Y.P.D.!
3XK在哪
Where is 3XK?
他在哪
Where is he?!
你还好吗  警探
How are you, detective?
那要看卡尔·马修斯这边进展如何
Depends on how things go down with carl matthews.
我让你们单独待会儿
I'll give you two the room.
医生
Doctor.
长官
Sir.
什么样的变态混蛋为了一些卷宗杀两个人啊
What kind of twisted bastard murders two people for some files?
就他那种
That kind.
有证据证明是他杀了他了吗
Do we have proof that he killed him?
证据不足
Not enough.
那接下来怎么办
So what's gonna happen?
我们要让他以为我们掌握的证据比实际的多
We make him think that our case is stronger than it really is,
让他招供
Get him to confess.
这是我们唯一的办法
It's our only play.
你弄断了我三根肋骨
You broke three of my ribs.
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我本来打算弄断两位数的呢
I was going for double digits.
我们要坦白地聊聊你的未来了  卡尔
We need to have a candid conversation about your future, Carl.
或者说没有未来
Or lack thereof.
我们在你背的背包里发现了钢制钓丝
We found a steel fishing line in that backpack you were carrying.
有趣的是
Here's a fun fact.
你知道当你切当一根金属丝时
Did you know that when you cut a wire,
它会留下微观的痕迹
it leaves microscopic impressions--
独一无二的金属微观痕迹
unique microscopic impressions-- in the metal.
我们因此知道背包里的这根线
That's how we knew the wire in the pack
和你用来吊丹尼尔·桑托斯的是同一卷线
came from the same spool that you used to hang Daniel Santos.
我们能证明你与帕姆·霍奇斯的死有关
We can also connect you to the murder of Pam Hodges.
同样的钓丝  同样的切割工具
Same wire, same cutting tool.
还有佛罗里达的谋杀案
And to the murders in Florida.
没错
Oh, yes.
你钟爱的钓丝又一次出现了
Where your fondness for fishing line was once again on display.
但我认为在法庭上
But I think by this point in the trial,
陪审团听到这里就够了
the jurors will have heard enough.
听起来只有大棒没有胡萝卜啊
Sounds like a lot of sticks and no carrots.
都招了吧  卡尔
Confess to all the murders, Carl.
佛罗里达那边会免去死刑
And Florida will take the death penalty off the table.
这是你能得到最好的条件
It's the best you're gonna get.
我是给你求生的机会
I'm giving you life.
这比你给死者的多多了
Which is more than you ever gave your victims.
好吧
All right.
我都成功得手了
I had a good run.
有几起案件
How many are there?
一路往北有四起  如果你是要问这个
Way north of four, if that's what you're asking.
跟我说说帕姆·霍奇斯
Tell me about Pam Hodges.
她是个斗士
She was a fighter.
她脸上的表情
And the look on her face--
她渴望活下来
She wanted to live so bad.
但我让她站在运输托盘上  然后把它抽走
But I stood her on a shipping pallet, then pulled it away.
她的双脚刚好离地
And her feet were just... just off the ground.
我记得她的鞋尖摩擦着木板
I remember the toes of her shoes scuffing the wood.
一开始是慌张而迅速地
All panicky and fast, at first.
然后慢下来
And then slower.
最后停了下来
And then not at all.
那丹尼尔·桑托斯呢
And what about Daniel Santos?
对丹尼尔  我用的是卷线器
With Daniel, I used the reel.
我每收缩四分之一英寸  发出滴答的声响
So with each click I drew in a quarter-inch of line.
线就变得更紧
It got tighter...
然后把他一点一点吊起来
And then lifted him bit... by bit.
我每听到滴答一声  我就去看他
Every time I hear a click, I'm right back with him.
你觉得我们要花多久
How long do you think it's gonna take
才能不去想他的所作所为
before we stop thinking about what he's done?
直到我们
Till we stop...
不再看着对方  就好像看着两个死人
looking at each other and seeing two dead people?
我不知道
I don't know.
你为了杰瑞·泰森杀了他们
You killed them both for Jerry Tyson.
不  我欣赏他的杰作
No, I admire his work.
但不是这样  我只为自己卖命
But no, I'm my own man.
你为了自己  让他们改头换面
And as your own man, you groomed them,
用你在开曼群岛建的
paid for Pam's apartment using the money
格莱格斯·贝克公司账户里的钱为帕姆付房租
from the Gregs-Baker account that you established in the Caymans.
对  是这样的
Yeah, that's right.
你在说谎
You're lying.
开户地点是在伯利兹  不是在开曼
That account was opened in Belize, not the Caymans.
因为你不是开户人  所以你不知道
But you wouldn't know that because you weren't the one who opened it.
杰瑞·泰森在哪
Where's Jerry Tyson?
据我所知他已经死了
Uh, he's dead is my understanding.
那你何必大费周章偷3XK的案卷
So then why did you do all of this to steal the 3XK files?
你为什么入住同样的汽车旅馆
Why would you use the same motel?
住在杰瑞·泰森逃出警方监控的房间里
The same room where Jerry Tyson escaped police custody?
有人推荐了那里
Someone recommended it.
另外无线上网免费
Plus it had free wi-fii.
我会供认我杀过的人
I'll confess to my kills.
一个不多  一个不少
No more and no less.
我还记得他们每一个人
I recall every one of them
细节记忆犹新
in the clearest detail.
所有的记忆
All those memories.
对我来说  我不会住在牢房里
And to me, I won't be in a prison cell.
而是会活在脑海里
I'll be living here.
我需要杆好笔和一个本
Uh, I need a good pen and a pad of paper.
其实  是好几个本
Uh, several pads, in fact.
我知道你们觉得把一切都搞清了
I know you think you've got this all figured out,
但是你们没有
But you don't.
他是怎么说杰瑞·泰森的
What did he say about Jerry Tyson?
什么都没说
Nothing.
这些文件被盗是个重大的安全漏洞
The theft of those files was a major security breach.
警局会很快把这件事糊弄过去的
Be aware that the department is eager to put that behind them.
这很丢人
It's an embarrassment.
长官  如果有探长提出泰森
Sir, if a detective were to suggest that tyson,
这个当局已经宣布死亡的人
a man that the department's already declared dead,
可能还活着
might still be alive--
那就更丢人了
An even bigger embarrassment.
所以如果你要提出这一观点
So if you're gonna make that claim...
要保证有理有据
make damn sure you can back it up.
我会记住的  长官
I will keep that in mind, Sir.
刚才说什么了
What was that about?
如果泰森还活着  纽约警局也不想知道
That if Tyson is alive, the N.Y.P.D. doesn't wanna know about it.
那你呢
And what about you?
你觉得他回来了吗
Do you think he's back?
卡塞尔  没有人能死而复生
Castle, people don't just rise from the dead.
所以我还在寻找其他解释
So I'm still looking at other explanations.
但是如果他真逍遥法外  我们得找到他
But if he is out there, we have to find him.
我们从卡尔·马修斯那里得不到什么了
We're not gonna get any more out of Carl Matthews.
那我们从哪里开始
So... where do we start?
伙计们
Guys,
我觉得我在发过来的监狱报告中有所发现
I think I found something in those prison records that got sent over.
你们还记得泰森在被释放前
Do you remember right before he was released from prison,
被狱友殴打了吗
Tyson got beat up by some inmates?
对  这就是我们把他放出来的原因
Yeah, that's why we pulled him out of there.
我们以为他有生命危险
We thought his life was in danger,
但是结果是他导演的这一切
But it turns out, he just staged the whole thing.
对  但是殴打是真的
Right, but the beat down was real.
他被送到了医务室
He got sent to the infirmary.
看看是谁治疗了他
Look who was attending him.
凯莉·尼曼医生
Dr. Kelly Nieman?
她志愿成为一名监狱医生
She volunteered as a prison doc.
更重要的是  她在泰森到那儿的那周开始工作
More importantly, she started there the week Tyson arrived,
他释放后她就辞职了
and she quit the day he was released.
她以前就认识他
She knew him from before.
她是为了接近他才接下这个工作
She took that job to be close to him.
她是泰森的女朋友
She's gotta be Tyson's girlfriend.
他把自己会的一切都教给了她
He taught her everything he knew.
把她带回来
Get her back here.
她不接电话
She's not answering her cell.
也不在公寓里
She's not at her apartment either.
该死
Damn it!
这就是你找不到她的原因
This explains why you couldn't reach her.
她跑了
She bolted.
如果这和泰森有关  他肯定也跑了
And if Tyson's in this, he did, too.
这家诊所生机勃勃的样子还历历在目呢
Seems like only yesterday this place was a thriving medical practice,
但是  都过去了
but... it was yesterday.
我们还是需要检查这个地方
We still gotta clear the place.
贝克特
Beckett?
怎么了
What is it?
好的  谢谢
Okay, all right, thanks.
所有3XK案卷的电子记录也都被删除了
So all of the electronic records from the 3xk cases were deleted, too.
不仅如此  似乎被害人
Not only that, but it looks like our victims
拿走了其他26起悬案的证据和文件
took evidence and files from 26 other unsolved murders.
那些案子也是泰森干的吗
More murders committed by Tyson?
或者是凯莉·尼曼
Or Kelly Nieman.
我说不清  卡塞尔
I don't know, Castle.
我开始觉得她也有这个能力
I'm starting to think she'd be capable of it, too.
泰森确实是挑对了女人
Tyson sure did pick the right woman.
而且她还能改变他的容貌
Plus she can change his appearance.
没准她已经这么干了
Maybe she already has.
你是觉得他还活着
You're still assuming that he's alive.
你不这么认为吗
Aren't you?
他一定还活着
He must be.
否则  为什么要安排这一切偷走文件呢
Otherwise, why orchestrate all this to steal the file?
或许她只是想留住他的记忆
Well, maybe she just wanted to keep his memory alive.
或者是他的遗产
Or his legacy.
这让他们两个人一样危险
And that makes her just as dangerous as he is.
她还在逍遥法外
She's still out there somewhere
和杰瑞·泰森在一起  或独自一人
with Jerry Tyson or without him.
*我们还会再见*
*We'll meet again*
*虽不知何地*
*Don't know where*
*虽不知何时*
*Don't know when*
*但我知道你我一定会再见*
*But I know we'll meet again*
*在一个阳光灿烂的日子*
*Some sunny day*
*要一直微笑*
*Keep smiling through*
*正如你*
*Just like you*
*一直以来的那样*
*Always do*
*直到蓝天*
*Till the blue skies*
*将乌云*
*Drive the dark clouds*
*驱散*
*Far away*